MICHAEL MELLO PAPERS (APAP287) 1800-2008
M. E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives
- Research Files, 1800-2004; 7; 14
  - Jurisdiction-Deliquency, Volume IV of IX, ca. 1977 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - "The Jurisdiction to do Justice: Florida's Jury Override and the State Constitution" by Michael Mello-Research, 1848; 1853; 1857-1858; 1876-1877; 1881-1882 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - "The Jurisdiction to do Justice: Florida's Jury Override and the State Constitution" by Michael Mello-Research, 1891; 1894; 1896-1897; 1902; 1991 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - "The Jurisdiction to do Justice: Florida's Jury Override and the State Constitution" by Michael Mello-Research, 1907-1908; 1924; 1926; 1937; 1960 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - "The Jurisdiction to do Justice: Florida's Jury Override and the State Constitution" by Michael Mello-Research, 1963; 1966; 1968; 1972-1974; 1976-1977 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - "The Jurisdiction to do Justice: Florida's Jury Override and the State Constitution" by Michael Mello-Research (1 of 4), 1979; 1990; 1992; Undated (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - "The Jurisdiction to do Justice: Florida's Jury Override and the State Constitution" by Michael Mello-Research (2 of 4), 1979-1990; 1992; Undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - "The Jurisdiction to do Justice: Florida's Jury Override and the State Constitution" by Michael Mello-Research (3 of 4), 1979-1990; 1992; Undated (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - "The Jurisdiction to do Justice: Florida's Jury Override and the State Constitution" by Michael Mello-Research (4 of 4), 1979-1990; 1992; Undated (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - "Jurisprudence and Gender" by Robin West, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - "Jurisprudence and Legal Philosphy in Twentieth-Century America-Major Themes an Developments" by Martin P. Goulding, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Jurry Override, 1976; 1985-1990; 1992; Undated (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - "Justice After Trial: Prisoners' Need for Legal Services in the Criminal- Correctional Process" by Jacob and Sharma, 1970 (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - "Justice Black and Equal Protection" by Tinsley E. Yarbrough, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - "Justice Black: Local Control and Federalism" by O'Rourke and Thernstrom, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - "Justice Brennan and the Jurisprudence of Dissent" by Laura Krugman Ray, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - "Justice Brennan, The Constitution and Modern American Liberalism" by David Rudenstine, 1988 (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Justice Grants, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - "Justice Harlan" by Robert T. McCracken, 1912 (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - "Justice O'Conner on Executions", 2001 (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - "Justice Thurgood Marshall: Advocate for Human Need in American Jurisprudence" by William J. Brennan, JR., 1981 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Juvenile and Family Court Journal: The Juvenile Court and Serious Offenders 38 Recommendations, 1984 Summer (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Juvenile and Family Courts by William H. Sheridan, 1984 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - "The Juvenile Court and the Adversary system: Problems of Function and Form" by Joel F. Handler, 1965 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Juvenile Court Statistics 1984- U.S. Department of Justice, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - "The Juvenile Death Penalty" by Warren M. Kato, 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - "The Juvenile Death Penalty: Counsel's Role in the Dependent of a Mitigation Defense" by Marla M. Homan, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - "The Juvenile Death Penalty: In the Best Interests of the Child?" by Suzanne D. Strater, 1995 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - "The Juvenile Death Penalty in Washington: A State Constitutional Analysis" by Bruce L. Brown, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - "The Juvenile Death Penalty Today: Death Sentences and Executions for Juvenile Crimes, January 1, 1973-December 31, 2003" by Victor Sreib, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Juvenile Death Sentencing Statistics, Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Juvenile Deliquency by Clemens Bartallas- Excerpt, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Juvenile Executions in the United States since 1977- Amnesty International, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Juvenile Homicide Case Data, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - "Juvenile Justice Reform: An Historical Perspective" by Sanford J. Fox, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Juvenile Justice Standards-Transfer between Courts-IJA-ABA Joint Commission, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - "Juvenile Offenders Could Avoid Execution Florida May Join A National Trend and Strike the Death Penalty in Such Cases" by Maya Bell, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - "Juvenile and the Death Penalty" by Lynn Cothern, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Juveniles and the Death Penalty- Experts, Undated (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Juveniles Executed in Georgia since 1900, Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Keeney v. Tamayo-Reyes, 1992 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Kentucky Penal Code 532.025, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - "Kids Who Kill: A Critique of How the American Legal System Deals with Juveniles who Commit Homicide" by Mirah A. Horowitz, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Knight v. Dugger, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Lanier v. Fairfield Communities Inc., 1990 (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Lau v. Nichols, 1973-1974 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - "Law and Gender: The Feminist Project in Action" by Kim Rosser, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - "Law and Politics in the New Republic", 1966 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - "Law as a moral Judgement vs. Law as the Rules of the Powerful" by Beyleveld and Brownsword, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - LeCroy v. Florida, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - LeCroy v. Florida, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Legal Positivism/ legal Realism- Hart/ Rogat, Undated (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - The Legal Status of Adolescents 1980- A Report of the Dept. of Health and Human Services ( 1 of 3), 1981 (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - The Legal Status of Adolescents 1980- A Review of the Dept. of Health and Human Services ( 2 of 3), 1981 (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - The Legal Status of Adolescents 1980- A Report of the Dept. of Health and Human Services (3 of 3), 1981 (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Legislative Session- December, 1986; 1985-1986; Undated (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Legislative Session-January- March 1986, Undated (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Legislative Session- January- March 1987, Undated (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Legislative Session-January-March 1988, Undated (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Legislative Session- June 1987, Undated (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Legislative Session-March 1986-January 1987, Undated (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - "Legislative Highlights of 1991" by Morty Rosenbaum, ca.1991 (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - "Legitimating Death" by Louis D. Bilionis, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - "The Legitimation of Purposive Decisions" by Philipepe Nonet, 1980 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Lewis v. Florida, 1986 (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Lewis v. Florida, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - "The Life Span of a Judge-Made Rule" by John Paul Stevens, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Lindabury v. Landabury, 1988-1989 (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - List of Juveniles-Detailed Complaint Breakdown, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - List of State Legislation Concerning Juveniles, 2004 (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - "Lon Fuller and Substantive Natural Law" by Anthony D' Amato, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - "The Long Road up from Barbarism: Thurgood Marshall and the Death Penalty" by Jordan Streiker, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Long v. Florida, 1988 (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Lozada v. Deeds, 1991 (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Major Issues in Juvenile Justice Information and Training: Youth in Adult Courts: Between Two Worlds- U.S. Department of Justice ( 1 of 2), 1982 (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Major Issues in Juvenile Justice Information and Training: Youth in Adult Courts: Between Two Worlds- U.S. Department of Justice ( 2 of 2), 1982 (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 1 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 2 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 3 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 4 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 5 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 6 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 7 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 8 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 9 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 10 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 11 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 12 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 13 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 14 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 15 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 16 of 19), 1972-1993 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 17 of 19), 1973-1993 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 18 of 19), 1973-1993 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Relentless Dissents- Marshall Papers ( 19 of 19), 1973-1999 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - US Code Service, Crimes and Criminal Procedure, Undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Mason v. Arizona, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Massachusetts Board of Retirement v. Murgia, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Matlock v. Rose, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Maxwell v. Florida, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - May v. Anderson, 1953 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Warren McCleskey (1 of 2), 1984-1987; 1991; Undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Warren McCleskey (2 of 2), 1984-1987; 1991; Undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - "McClesky v. Kemp'. Race, Capital Punishment, and the Supreme Court" by Randall L. Kennedy, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - McCollom v. Bush, 1965 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - McCorquodale v. Kemp, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - McCrae v. Florida, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - McDowell v. Dixon, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - McDuffic v. Sellers-Bok, 1995 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - McKeiver v. Pennsylvania, 1971 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Dock McKay, 1989-1990 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - "The meaning and Nature of the Natural Law in Thomas Aquinas" by William E. May, 1977 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - " Mechanical Jurisprudence" by Roscoe Pound, 1908 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - "Meditation form a Feminist Perspective: Promise and Problems" by Janet Rifkin, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Medical Malpractice, 1960; 1967; 1982; 1988; Undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Meeks v. Dugger, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Memo in Support of an Act to Amend the Penal Law, Undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Memorandrum in Opposition to S. 600/ A. 1070- New York Lawyers Against the Death Penalty, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Meneses v. Florida, 1979 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - "Merciful Juries: The Resilience of Jury Nullification" by Scheflin and Van Dyke, 1991 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Messer v. Florida, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - Middleton v. Dugger, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - " The Metaphor of Standing and the Problem of Self- Governance" by Steven L. Winter, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Middleton v. State/ Caldwell Claims, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Mikenas v. Dugger, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - "Militarism, Male Dominance and Law: Feminist Jurisprudence as Oxymoron?" by Ann Scales, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 35)
  - "Mind's Opportunity: Birthing a Postructuralist Feminist Jurisprudence" by Marie Ashe, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Minimum Statutory Ages for the Death Penalty- Eighth Edition by Victor Streib, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - "Minors' Competence to Consent to Abortion" by Catherine C. Lewis, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 38)
  - Missouri v. Simmons, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 39)
  - Missouri v. Wilkins, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 40)
  - William Neal Moore, 1984; 1988 (Box 10, Folder 41)
  - Moore v. Southwestern Bell Telephone Co., 1979 (Box 10, Folder 42)
  - Moore's Ford Murder, 1972 (Box 10, Folder 43)
  - "Moratorium on the Death Penalty for Juveniles" by Victor Streib, 1988 (Box 10, Folder 44)
  - Morgan, 1989 (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Morgan v. Florida -FLSC- Opinion, 1987 (Box 10, Folder 46)
  - Morris v. State, 1984 (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - "Mr.Justice Arthur J. Goldberg and the Death Penalty: A memorandum to the Conference" by Robert S. Marsel, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 48)
  - " Mr. Justice Black and the Judicial Function" by Paul A. Freund, 1967 (Box 10, Folder 49)
  - " Mr. Justice William Johnson and the Constitution" by Donald G. Morgan, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 50)
  - "Mr. Justice William Johnson and the Uneviable Dilemma" by A.J. Levin, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 51)
  - "Mr. Justice William Johnson, Creative Dissenter" by A.J. Levin, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 52)
  - "Mr. Justice William Johnson, Jurist in Limine" by A.J. Levin, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 53)
  - Murray v. Carrier, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 54)
  - Musgrove v. Alabama, 1982 (Box 10, Folder 55)
  - NAACP Legal Defense Fund - Capital Punishment Conference-List of Names, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - "Natural Law"- Naturalism in Ethics, Richard Walhelm, Undated (Box 10, Folder 57)
  - Bridging the Gap: Transitional Benefits- What are they? An Overview and Survey of 15 Countries, Undated (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - " The Nature of Judicial Review" by Harry H. Wellington, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - " The Nature of Precedent" by Earl Maltz, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Nelson Textbook of Pediatrics, Twelfth Edition by Behram and Voughan- Excerpts, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - "Neuropsychiatric, Psychoeducational, and Family Characteristics of 14 Juveniles Condemned to Death in the United States" by Dorothy Ornow Lew, et al., 1988 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - " Neutral Principles in the 1950's" by Gary Peller, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - New Jersey v. J.Q., 1992 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - New Jesey v. Michaels, Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - New Jersey v. Reed- Affadavit of Leigh Bienen, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - New Jersey v. T.L.O, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - New York v. Ferber, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - New York v. McKiernan, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - New York v. Romer, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - The New Yorker, 1990 March 12 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Newlon v. Armontrovt, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper Analysis, 1962; 1988; 1992-1994; 2002-2004; Undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - "Non Occides: Thurgood Marshall and the Death Penalty" by William J. Daniels, 1977 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - "Normative and Nowhere to Go" by Pierre Schlag, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Notes on Hitchcock Harmless Error Cases, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - NYS Assembly-1995 Committee Bill Memorandum (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - NYS Bills S.2850 and A.4843, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - O'Callaghan v. State, 1989 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - "Off the Pedestal and Onto the Block? Motherhood, Reproductive Technologies, and the Canadian State" by Somer Brodribb, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - Old Race Statutes, 1822; 1828; 1830; 1832; 1840 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Old Race Statutes, 1847; 1850; 1865-1866; 1868; 1881 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Old Race Statutes, 1891; 1892; 1894; 1917; 1921 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Old Race Statutes, 1923; 1953; 1959; 1962-1963; 1966-1967 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Old Race Statutes, 1972; 1982; 1990; Undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - "On Teaching Feminist Jurisprudence" by Liana Fiol Matta, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - "On the Front Line: Law Enforcement Views on the Death Penalty" by Richard C. Dieter, 1995 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - "On the Perils of Line- Drawing: Juveniles and the Death Penalty"- Joseph L. Hoffman, 1988 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Order of Supreme Court from the Supreme Court of Ohio Following Lockett v. Ohio, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Oregon v. Mitchell, 1970 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - "Origins of the Unwritten Constitution: Fundemental Law in American Revolutionary Thought" by Thomas C. Grey, 1978 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Parham v. J.R., 1978 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - " Passionate Scholarship: Notes on values, knowing and method in feminist social science" by Barbara DuBois, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - "The Path of Law"- Justice Holmes, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - "Patterns of Death: An Analysis of Racial Dispanties in Cultural Sentencing and Homicide Victimization" by Gross and Mauro, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Payne v. Virginia, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Pedrero v. Wainwright, 1979 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - "Penal Sanctions as a Feminist Strategy: A Contradiction in Terms? Pornography and Criminal Law in Netherlands" by Brants and Kok, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Pennsylvania v. Finley, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - John Paul Penry, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - People v. Carpenter, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - People v. Smith, 1984 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Percy v. Vermont, 1991 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Perkins v. Texas, 1994 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Persons Executed for Crimes Committed While Under Age Eighteen- Fifth Edition by Victor Streib, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - Persons on Death Row as of June 24, 1988, for Crimes Committed While Under Age Eighteen by Victor Streib (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - "Perspectives on Women's Subordination and the Role of Law" by Taub and Schneider, 1982 (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - Petition of James Terry Roach for Commutation of Sentence of Death, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - Police Officers For Equal Rights v. City of Col., 1985 (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - Portia in a Different Voice: Speculations on a Women's Lawyering Process" By Carrie Menkel- Meadow, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 53)
  - Postconviction Remedies by Larry Yackle, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 54)
  - "Post- Furman Botched Executions" by Michael L. Radelet, 2004 (Box 11, Folder 55)
  - "Positivism and Fidelity to Law- A Reply to Professor Hart" by Lon L. Fuller, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 56)
  - "Positivism and the Separation of Law and Harris" by H.L.A. Hart, 1958 (Box 11, Folder 57)
  - Positivism, Utilitarianism, Natural Rights- The Idea of Justice, Undated (Box 11, Folder 58)
  - Preston v. Florida, 1990 (Box 11, Folder 59)
  - Priestman v. US, 1800 (Box 11, Folder 60)
  - "A Prisoner's Constitutional Right to Attorney Assistence" by Raymond Y. Lin, 1983 (Box 11, Folder 61)
  - The Prisoners' Mail Box and the Evolution of Federal Inmate Rights by Ira P. Robbins, 1993 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - "Pro Bono Representation of Death Sentenced Inmates" by John C. Godbold, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Proposed Amendment to CJA Plan for Southern District NY, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Proposed Death Penalty Law in New York, 1994-1996 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Proposed Grove City Legislation, Religious Liberty, and Private Education, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Proposed Standards, 1995 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Provenzano v. Dugger, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - "Psychiatric Problems of Adolescence" by Hunt and Cohen, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - The Psychology of Moral Development, Vol II by L. Kohlberg, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Public Defender, Undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Public Defense Services in Clinton County: An Assessment of the Assigned Counsel Program- Public Defense Backup Center, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Public Defense Services in New York State: Historical, Systemic, Case and Political Perspective by Jonathan E. Gradess, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Public Defense Services in Ontario Country- Public Defense Backup Center, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Public Defense Services in Schenectaady County: An Assessment of the Assigned Counsel Program- Public Defense Backup Center, 1984 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Punitiveness and Public Opinion on Abortion and Capital Punishment in the United States by Kimberly Cook- Doctoral Dissertation ( 1 of 2), 1994 (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Punitiveness and Public Opinion on Abortion and Capital Punishment in the United States by Kimberly Cook- Doctoral Dissertation ( 2 of 2), 1994 (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Quarles v. Oxford Mun. Separate School Dist., 1989 (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - "Race and Death: The Judicial Evaluation of Evidence of Discrimination in Capital Sentencing" by Samuel R. Gross, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - "Race, Racism, and Feminist Legal Theory" by Marke Kline, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - James David Raulerson, 1982; 1985 (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - "Realism, Feminism, Methodology, and Law" by Maureen Cain, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - "Realism, Nihilism, and the Supreme Court: Do the Emperors Have Nothing but Robes?" by John E. Nowak, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - "A Realistic Jurisprudence- The Next Step" by Karl N. Llewellyn, 1930 (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - "Reason and Death" by George F. Will, 2003 (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - "Reason, Passian, and the Progress of the Law"-The 42nd Annual Bejamin N. Cardozo Lecture- By William J. Brennon, JR., 1988 (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - "Reasoning in the Personal and Moral Domains: Adolescent and Young Adult Women's Decision- Making Regarding Abortion" by Judith Smetana, 1981 (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - "Recent Public Opinion on the Juvenile Death Penalty"- Death Penalty Information Center, 2004 (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - Rector v. Clinton, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - "Reflections on the Juvenile Death Penalty: Contravention of Precedent and Public Opinion" by Kim A. Lechner, 1997 (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - "Reflections on the significance of the sex /Gender System: Divorce Law Reform in New York" by Isabel Marcos, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Relentless Dissents- Research- Miscellaneous, 1815; 1940; 1987; 1989; 1991 (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - Remarks of the Chief Justice- American Bar Association Mid-Year Meeting, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - "Remarks on the Death Penalty Made at the Judicial Conference of the Second Circuit" by Thurgood Marshall, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - Report of the Florida Bar Commission to Study Practical Aspects of Death Sentence Appeals, 1991 (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Representation of Indigent Defendants, 1954 (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - Representation of Indigent Defendants ( 1 of 2), 1959 (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Representation of Indigent Defendants ( 2 of 2), 1959 (Box 12, Folder 37)
  - Representation of Indigent Defendants, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - Representation of Indigent Defendants, 1962 (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Representation of Parties, Undated (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - "Reproductive Ethics: Feminist and Non-Feminist Approaches" by Christine Overall, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - "The Requirement of Death: Mandatory Language in the Pennsylvania Death Penalty Statute" by Bruce S. Ledewitz, 1982 (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - "Re-Reading Contracts: A Feminist Analysis of Contracts Casebook" by Mary Joe Frug, 1985 (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - Review of Child Development Research, Volume one Edited by Hoffman and Hoffman- Excerpts, 1964 (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - "Right to Aid in Addition to Councel for Indigent Criminal Defendents", 1963 (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - "Right to Counsel in Criminal Post-Conviction Review Proceedings" by Gordon H. Van Kessel, 1963 (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - "The Right to Privacy" by Warren and Brandeis, 1890 (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - Riley v. Wainwright, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Risking the Future: Adolescent Sexuality, Pregnancy, and Childbearing, Volume I, Edited by Cheryl D. Hayes, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Ross v. Moffitt, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - Ruffin v. Dugger, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - S. 2455, 1988 (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Saffle v. Parks, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Satterwhite v. Texas, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - School v. Arizona, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Schall v. Martin, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Schlup v. Delo, 1993-1994 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - "The Scope and Purpose of Sociological Jurisprudence" by Roscoe Pound, 1911 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - "Section Seeks Volunteers to Represent Death Row Inmates" by Micael B Hyman, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Selvage v. Lynaugh, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Senate Bill 150: Death Penalty- Minors, 1988 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - "Sexual Assault and the Feminist Judge" by Christine Boyle, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 10)